Otto Klemperer Archive
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Music, 1915-1971 (Box 1-43, 103-106, 108)
  - Works by Otto Klemperer (Box 1-37, 103-106, 108)
    - Die Weber, Parts, strings (photocopy of copyist's manuscript) (Box-folder 27/5)
    - Die Weber, Part, chorus, photocopies of copyist's manuscript (includes one transparency) (Box-folder 27/6)
    - Das Ziel [1915], Copyist's manuscript full score with emendations (Box-folder 28/1-4)
    - Das Ziel [1915], Photocopy of copyist's manuscript full score (Box-folder 29/1-2)
    - Das Ziel [1915], Printed piano-vocal score with emendations; On p. 5: Uncorrigiert; unerwartete Begegnung. (Box-folder 29/3)
    - Das Ziel [1915], Printed piano-vocal score with emendations; On p. 5: Uncorrigiert; Für Verlag. Laid in: typed notes in German (Box-folder 29/4)
    - Das Ziel [1970] I. Teil see also [Lieder] Frühlingsglaube, Holograph manuscript full score, I. Teil (Box-folder 30/1)
    - Das Ziel [1970] II. Scene [Teil], Holograph manuscript full score; At end: 22.3.1970 Zürich. (Box-folder 30/2)
    - Das Ziel [1970] 3 [III]. Teil, Holograph manuscript full score (Box-folder 30/3)
    - Das Ziel [1970] 4 [IV]. Teil, Holograph manuscript full score; At end: 15.11.70 Zürich. (Box-folder 30/4)
    - Das Ziel [1970] 4 [IV]. Teil, Copyist's manuscript full score (Box-folder 30/5-8)
    - Das Ziel [1970] 4 [IV]. Teil, Photocopy of copyist's manuscript full score (Box-folder 31/1-2)
    - Das Ziel [1970] 4 [IV]. Teil, Libretto (3 copies) (Box-folder 31/3)
    - Das Ziel [1970] 4 [IV]. Teil, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 31/4)
    - Das Ziel [1970] 4 [IV]. Teil, Photocopy of copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score with emendations (Box-folder 105/1)
    - Das Ziel [1970] 4 [IV]. Teil, Photocopy of copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 105/2-6)
    - Das Ziel [1970] 4 [IV]. Teil, Photocopy of copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (transparencies); Laid in: letter from Clem to Lotte Klemperer. (Box-folder 31/5)
    - Das Ziel [1970] 4 [IV]. Teil, Part, chorus (transparencies) (Box-folder 31/6)
    - Das Ziel [1970] 4 [IV]. Teil, Parts (transparencies); Laid in: orchestra part distribution in German. (Box-folder 32/1-2)
    - Das Ziel [1970] 4 [IV]. Teil, Photocopy parts (Box-folder 32-36)
  - Arrangements by Otto Klemperer (Box 38-40)
    Arranged alphabetically by composer, and by title therein.
    - Bach, Johann Sebastian. [Bist du bei mir, geh' ich mit Freuden]
      - Bist du bei mir?, Copyist's manuscript full score (transparencies) (Box-folder 38/1)
      - Bist du bei mir, geh' ich mit Freuden, Photocopy of copyist's manuscript full score (2 copies) (Box-folder 38/2)
      - Bist du bei mir?, Parts with markings (Box-folder 38/3)
    - Bach, Johann Sebastian. Ein' feste Burg ist unser Gott
      - Ein' feste Burg ist unser Gott, Holograph manuscript full score; At end: July 2, 1937. (Box-folder 38/4)
      - Ein' feste Burg ist unser Gott, Photocopy copyist's manuscript full score (2 copies) (Box-folder 38/4)
      - Ein' feste Burg ist unser Gott, Copyist's manuscript full score (transparencies) (Box-folder 38/5)
      - Ein' feste Burg ist unser Gott, Parts (Box-folder 38/6)
    - Bach, Johann Sebastian. Nun komm der Heiden Heiland
      - Nun komm der Heiden Heiland, Holograph manuscript full score; At end: 1935. (Box-folder 38/7)
      - Nun komm der Heiden Heiland, Copyist's manuscript full score (transparencies) (Box-folder 38/8)
      - Nun komm der Heiden Heiland, Photocopy of copyist's manuscript full score (2 copies) (Box-folder 38/9)
      - Nun komm der Heiden Heiland, Parts (Box-folder 38/10)
    - Bach, Johann Sebastian. Sonata in E-flat major
      - Sonata in E-flat major, Photocopy of copyist's manuscript full score with emendations; At end: (written app. 1937). (Box-folder 38/11)
      - Sonata in E-flat major, Parts (Box-folder 39/1-2)
    - Beethoven, Ludwig van. [Concerto, piano, no. 4, op. 58, G major]
      - Cadenz zu Satz I von Beethovens g-dur Konzert, Photocopy of holograph manuscript for piano; On t.p.: Original in Lonny Epstein Archive of the Juilliard School of Music. (Box-folder 39/3)
      - Cadenz zu Satz I von Beethovens g-dur Konzert, Copyist's manuscript for piano (Box-folder 39/3)
      - Cadenz zu Satz I von Beethovens g-dur Konzert, Photocopy of copyist's manuscript for piano; Laid in: possible corrections (suggested by Otto Freudenthal; letter dated 3.6.76). (Box-folder 39/3)
    - Gluck, Christoph Willibald. Arranged by Johannes Brahms. Gavotte
      - Gavotte, Holograph manuscript full score; At end: 1968. (Box-folder 39/4)
      - Gavotte, Copyist's manuscript full score (Box-folder 39/4)
      - Gavotte, Printed score for piano (Box-folder 39/4)
      - Gavotte, Parts (Box-folder 39/5)
      - Gavotte, Parts, strings (transparencies) (Box-folder 39/6)
    - Mendelssohn, Felix. [Symphony, no. 3, op. 56, A minor]
      - 3. Sinfonie, Neuer Schluss, Holograph manuscript full score; At end: 15.9.68 London. Laid in: Zum Programm des Konzerts [with illegible notations]. (Box-folder 39/7)
      - Neuer Schluss zum Finale der Symphonie Nr. 3 in a-Moll, Op. 36, Copyist's manuscript full score; Reproduction of copyist’s manuscript. (Box-folder 39/7)
      - Symphonie Nr. 3, Printed full score (Box-folder 39/7)
      - Symphonie Nr. 3, Parts (Box-folder 39/8)
    - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus. [Don Giovanni]
      - Don Giovanni overture (concert ending), Photocopy of copyist's manuscript full score with markings; Reproduction of original printed Mozart ending and of copyist’s manuscript of Klemperer’s concert ending. (Box-folder 40/1)
      - Don Juan ouverture, Printed full score of original Mozart work (Box-folder 40/1)
      - Don Giovanni: Konzertschluss der Ouverture, Photocopy of printed full score (Box-folder 40/1)
      - Don Giovanni (concert ending), Parts with markings (Box-folder 40/2)
    - Rameau, Jean-Philippe. [Gavotte with six variations]
      - Gavotte mit sechs Variationen, Photocopy of copyist's manuscript full score (2 copies); At end: Copyright 1968 by Otto Klemperer. (Box-folder 40/3)
      - Gavotte mit sechs Variationen, Photocopy of copyist's manuscript (2 copies); At end: Copyright Otto Klemperer 1968. (Box-folder 40/4)
      - Gavotte mit sechs Variationen, Copyist's manuscript full score (transparencies) (Box-folder 40/5)
      - Gavotte mit 6 Variationen, Parts (Box-folder 40/6-7)
  - Works by Others (Box 41-43)
    Includes holograph and copyists' manuscripts; full scores and parts, some with markings and annotations; photocopies; and printed music.
    - Abt, Franz
      - Anna Lise see Works by Others: Mendelssohn, Volkslied
      - Es hat nicht sollen sein see Works by Others: Mendelssohn, Volkslied
    - [Anonymous]
      - Des Sommers letzte Rose see Works by Others: Mendelssohn, Volkslied
    - Bach, Johann Sebastian. Die hohe Messe in H Moll, Printed full score with holograph markings (Box-folder 41/1)
    - Beethoven, Ludwig van. Fidelio see also Works by Others: Beyer, Ferdinand, Printed piano-vocal score with holograph notes (Box-folder 41/2)
    - Beethoven, Ludwig van. Missa solemnis, Printed full score with holograph markings (Box-folder 41/3)
    - Beyer, Ferdinand, arranger. Opern-Album IV., Printed piano scores; Note: includes six other works. (Box-folder 41/4)
    - Brahms, Johannes. Robert Keller, arranger. Ungarische Tänze, Printed piano score for four hands with markings (Box-folder 42/1)
    - Brün, Herbert. Nonet (1969), Photocopy of manuscript full score (Box-folder 42/2)
    - Freudenthal, Otto. 12 Veränderungen einer zwölftonreihe, Printed score (Box-folder 42/5)
    - Freudenthal, Otto. 12 Veränderungen einer zwölftonreihe, Photocopy of printed score (Box-folder 42/5)
    - Freudenthal, Otto. Allegro, Intermezzo und Fine, Printed piano-viola score (Box-folder 42/3)
    - Freudenthal, Otto. Allegro, Intermezzo und Fine, Photocopy of printed piano-viola score (Box-folder 42/3)
    - Freudenthal, Otto. Allegro, Intermezzo und Fine, Printed viola part (Box-folder 42/4)
    - Freudenthal, Otto. Allegro, Intermezzo und Fine, Photocopy of printed viola part (Box-folder 42/4)
    - Klemperer, Johanna. Das wundervollste Licht, Photocopy of manuscript piano-vocal score; At end: Köln 3. Febr. 1922; Aufgeschrieben von Otto Klemperer. (Box-folder 42/6)
    - Klemperer, Ida. Adaun Aulom, Manuscript voice part (5 copies) (Box-folder 42/7)
    - Klemperer, Ida. Adaun Aulom, Photocopy of manuscript voice part (5 copies) (Box-folder 42/7)
    - Klemperer, Ida. Der du von dem Himmel bist see also Klemperer, Ida and Otto: Wandrer's Nachtlied, Manuscript piano-vocal score (2 copies) (Box-folder 42/8)
    - Klemperer, Ida. Der du von dem Himmel bist see also Klemperer, Ida and Otto: Wandrer's Nachtlied, Photocopy of manuscript (Box-folder 42/8)
    - Klemperer, Ida. [untitled], Photocopy of manuscript piano score (2 copies); On p. 1 of 1 copy: (Aufgeschrieben von Otto Klemperer). At end: zum 28. Oktober 1920. (Box-folder 42/9)
    - [Klemperer, Ida?] Abschied, Holograph manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 42/10)
    - [Klemperer, Ida?] [Illegible], Manuscript piano score (Box-folder 42/11)
    - [Klemperer, Ida?] [Illegible], Photocopy of manuscript piano score (2 copies) (Box-folder 42/11)
    - [Klemperer, Ida?] [Illegible], Manuscript vocal score (Box-folder 42/12)
    - [Klemperer, Ida?] [Illegible], Photocopy of manuscript vocal part (Box-folder 42/12)
    - [Klemperer, Ida?] [Untitled], Manuscript vocal sketch (Box-folder 42/13)
    - Klemperer, Ida and O[tto] Wandrer's Nachtlied see also Klemperer, Ida: Der du von dem Himmel bist, Copyist's manuscript piano-vocal score (Box-folder 42/14)
    - Klemperer, N[athan] [Exercise book] (Box-folder 42/15)
    - Lachner, Ignaz. Bellarosa see Works by Others: Mendelssohn, Volkslied
    - Lachner, Ignaz. Das Ständchen see Works by Others: Mendelssohn, Volkslied
    - Liebe, Ludwig. Auf Wiedersehn! see Works by Others: Mendelssohn, Volkslied
    - Lortzing, [Albert] Undine see Works by Others: Beyer, Ferdinand
    - Lortzing, [Albert] Waffenschmied see Works by Others: Beyer, Ferdinand
    - Mendelssohn, Felix. Drei Lieder, no. 1, Da lieg' ich unter den Bäumen see Works by Others: Mendelssohn, Volkslied
    - Mendelssohn, Felix. Symphonie Nr. 3 see Arrangements by Otto Klemperer: Mendelssohn, [Symphony, no. 3, Op. 56, A minor]
    - Mendelssohn, Felix. Volkslied, Printed piano-vocal score; Copy includes seven printed and one copyist's manuscript piano-vocal scores (Box-folder 42/16)
    - [Meyerbeer, Giacomo] Afrikanerin see Works by Others: Beyer, Ferdinand
    - Meierbeer, G. Romanze aus der Oper, die Hugenotten see Works by Others: Mendelssohn, Volkslied
    - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus. Cosi fan tutte, Printed piano-vocal score with markings (Box-folder 42/17)
    - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus. Don Giovanni overture see Arrangements by Otto Klemperer: Mozart, [Don Giovanni]
    - Nicolai, Otto. Lustige Weiber see Works by Others: Beyer, Ferdinand
    - Schumann, Robert. Der arme Peter, Printed piano-vocal score (Box-folder 43/1)
    - Stravinsky, Igor. Oedipus Rex, Printed piano-vocal score with notations (Box-folder 43/2)
    - Taubert, W. Mein Lisel see Works by Others: Mendelssohn, Volkslied
    - Verdi, Giuseppe. Falstaff, Printed piano-vocal score with markings (Box-folder 43/3)
    - Verdi, Giuseppe. Der Troubadour (Il Trovatore) see Works by Others: Mendelssohn, Volkslied
    - Waldmann, Ludolf. Schau' in's Auge deinem Kinde see Works by Others: Mendelssohn, Volkslied
    - Weber, [Carl Maria von] Oberon see Works by Others: Beyer, Ferdinand
- Family Papers, 1792-1983 (Box 44-45, 100, 106, Mapcase 3)
  Includes biographical dictionary entries; curriculum vitae; genealogies and genealogical notes; articles and letters both by and about family members; printed, photocopied, and handwritten materials.
  Arranged alphabetically by family name and subject.
  - Family trees (Mapcase-drawer 3/2)
  - Klemperer, Georg
    - Biographical information (Box-folder 44/1)
    - Letters, lecture (Box-folder 100/1)
  - Klemperer, Josef (Box-folder 44/2)
  - Klemperer/Klopper, Josef (Box-folder 44/3)
  - Klemperer, Nathan (Box-folder 44/4)
  - Klemperer, Victor
    - Clippings (Box-folder 106/5)
    - Curriculum vitae (Box-folder 44/5-7)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 44/8)
  - Klemperer family: biographical dictionary (Box-folder 44/9)
  - Klemperer: others (Box-folder 44/10)
  - Rée family (Box-folder 45/1)
- Correspondence, 1915-1974 (Box 45, 100)
  Includes original handwritten and typed letters, with some photocopies, to and from publishing companies; lists of items donated to educational institutions; and photocopies of cover pages of music, newspaper clippings, and correspondence.
  Arranged alphabetically by correspondents’ name.
  - B. Schott's Söhne (Box-folder 45/2)
  - California State University
    - Donation (Box-folder 45/3)
  - Otto Klemperer Archive
    - Catalogue listings of music (Box-folder 45/4)
    - Photocopy of music title pages (Box-folder 100/2)
  - Clem see Works by Otto Klemperer, Das Ziel
  - Eösze see Works by Otto Klemperer, Aria (Sehnsucht)
  - Freudenthal, Otto see Arrangements by Otto Klemperer, Cadenz zu Satz I von Beethovens g-dur Konzert
  - Homolya see Works by Otto Klemperer, Aria (Sehnsucht)
  - Klemperer, Lotte see Works by Otto Klemperer, Aria (Sehnsucht)
  - Klemperer, Lotte see Works by Otto Klemperer, Thamar
  - Osthoff, Wolfgang see Works by Otto Klemperer, Kreuz der Strasse
  - Royal Academy of Music, London (Box-folder 45/5)
  - Santa Monica College (Box-folder 45/6)
  - Universal Edition, 1909-1932 (Box-folder 45/7-8)
  - Universal Edition: Alfred Schlee, 1946-1948 (Box-folder 45/9)
- Writings, 1914-1981 (Box 46-48)
  - By Otto Klemperer (Box 46)
    Contains published and unpublished items, including typescripts, carbon copies, photocopies, printed materials, newspaper clippings, lectures, speeches, letters about music and musicians, and statements on unrelated topics.
    - An die Wiener Philharmoniker (Box-folder 46/1)
    - Bach, Johann Sebastian (Box-folder 46/2)
    - Bartók, Belá (Box-folder 46/3)
    - Beecham, Sir Thomas (Box-folder 46/4)
    - Beethoven, Ludwig van (Box-folder 46/5)
    - Berg, Alban (Box-folder 46/6)
    - Berlin Philharmonic Choir (Box-folder 46/7)
    - Bruckner, Anton (Box-folder 46/8)
    - Die Budapester Jahre (Box-folder 46/9)
    - Compositions of Otto Klemperer (Box-folder 46/10)
    - Conducting by memory or with score (Box-folder 46/11)
    - Contemporary music (Box-folder 46/12)
    - Der Dirigent Klemperer (Box-folder 46/13)
    - Der Dirigent Toscanini (Box-folder 46/14)
    - Drei Opernhäuser (Box-folder 46/15)
    - Dülberg, Ewald (Box-folder 46/16)
    - Felsenstein, Walter (Box-folder 46/17)
    - Der Geistige und der Sport (Box-folder 46/18)
    - Gespräch bei der Rückkehr nach Berlin (Box-folder 46/19)
    - Gluck's Orpheus and Eurydice (Box-folder 46/20)
    - Hindemith, Paul (Box-folder 46/21)
    - Klemperer's protest (Box-folder 46/22)
    - The Kroll Opera (Box-folder 46/23)
    - Künstler über sich selbst (Box-folder 46/24)
    - Los Angeles Philharmonic: speech before board of directors (Box-folder 46/25)
    - Mahler, Gustav (Box-folder 46/26)
    - Meine Erinnerungen an Lotte Lehman (Box-folder 46/27)
    - Meine Tätigkeit an der Kroll Oper (Box-folder 46/28)
    - Mendelssohn, Felix (Box-folder 46/29)
    - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus (Box-folder 46/30)
    - Music today (Box-folder 46/31)
    - My European spring tour in 1936 (Box-folder 46/32)
    - Occidental College speech (Box-folder 46/33)
    - Otto Klemperer writes about a show (Box-folder 46/34)
    - On my own behalf (Box-folder 46/35)
    - Order of Pour le Mérite speech (Box-folder 46/36)
    - Preamble to a talk to school boys (Box-folder 46/37)
    - Productive Kräfte sind am Werke (Box-folder 46/38)
    - Das Publikum im Opernhaus (Box-folder 46/39)
    - Saz, Natalia (Box-folder 46/40)
    - Schliessung der Kroll-Oper (Box-folder 46/41)
    - Schönberg, Arnold (Box-folder 46/42)
    - Shostakovich, Dimitri (Box-folder 46/43)
    - Sibelius, Jean (Box-folder 46/44)
    - Simmel, Georg (Box-folder 46/45)
    - Sovetskaya Filarmoniya (Box-folder 46/46)
    - Stanislavsky, Konstantin (Box-folder 46/47)
    - Stravinsky, Igor (Box-folder 46/48)
    - Tchaikowsky, Peter (Box-folder 46/49)
    - Three questions on New Year's Eve (Box-folder 46/50)
    - Über meine Budapester Jahre (Box-folder 46/51)
    - Wagner, Richard (Box-folder 46/52)
    - Working for art's sake (Box-folder 46/53)
    - Zemlinski, Alexander von (Box-folder 46/54)
  - About Otto Klemperer (Box 47)
    Contains published and unpublished materials, including typescripts; carbon copies; photocopies; printed materials; newspaper clippings; anecdotes and articles in English, German, other languages, and translations from Russian; and transcripts of broadcasts and film scripts.
    Arranged alphabetically by material type.
    - Anecdotes (Box-folder 47/1)
    - Articles in English (Box-folder 47/2)
    - Articles in German (Box-folder 47/3)
    - Articles translated from Russian (Box-folder 47/4)
    - Broadcasts (Box-folder 47/5)
    - Film scripts (Box-folder 47/6)
    - Miscellaneous items in various languages (Box-folder 47/7)
  - Interviews with Otto Klemperer (Box 47-48)
    Contains typescripts, photocopies, and carbon copies of interviews with Otto Klemperer, in English and German.
    Arranged alphabetically by interviewer.
    - Bregstein, Philo (Box-folder 47/8)
    - Freeman, John (Box-folder 47/9)
    - Gausmann, Ernst Ludwig (Box-folder 47/10)
    - Heyworth, Peter
      - Canadian Broadcasting Corporation (CBC) (Box-folder 48/1-4)
      - Westdeutsche Rundfunk (WDR) (Box-folder 48/5-6)
    - Kruttge, Eigel (Box-folder 48/7)
    - Metz, Louis (Box-folder 48/8)
- Legal and Financial Papers, 1934-1984 (Box 49)
  Includes Freedom of Information Act correspondence; citizenship certificates and passports; insurance policies; income tax returns; and correspondence with lawyers.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of organization or government agency, and chronologically therein.
  - Freedom of Information and Privacy Act (FOIPA)
    - Central Intelligence Agency (Box-folder 49/1)
    - Citizenship certificates/passports (Box-folder 49/2)
    - Federal Bureau of Investigation (Box-folder 49/3)
    - Freedom of Information Act (Box-folder 49/4)
    - Germany: expatriation correspondence (Box-folder 49/5)
    - Loeb and Loeb (Box-folder 49/11-13)
    - Northwestern Mutual Life Insurance Company (Box-folder 49/6)
  - State Department
    - Johanna Klemperer (Box-folder 49/7)
    - Lotte Klemperer (Box-folder 49/8)
    - Otto Klemperer (Box-folder 49/9)
    - Szinház és mozi (Box-folder 49/10)
- Kroll Opera, 1918-1965 (Box 50-51)
  Contains newspaper clippings, reviews and commentaries on specific performances, general information, photographs, programs, radio transcripts, and a dissertation on the Berlin State Opera.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material or subject.
  - Clippings
    - Concerts (Box-folder 50/1)
    - In eigener Sache (Box-folder 50/2)
    - Neues vom Tage (Box-folder 50/3)
  - Dissertation
    - Berlin State Opera, 1918-1931 (Box-folder 50/4)
  - General Information
    - Berlin (Box-folder 50/5)
    - Weiteres über Berlin, Prozess, Leipziger Unfall, etc. (Box-folder 50/6)
  - Photographs (Box-folder 50/7)
  - Programs (Box-folder 50/8)
  - Radio Transcripts
    - Südwest Radio (Box-folder 51/1)
    - West German Radio, 1961 (Box-folder 51/2)
    - West German Radio, 1962 (Box-folder 51/3)
  - Stage Designs
    - Bühnenbilder in Farbe (Box-folder 51/4)
  - Works Performed
    - Cardillac (Box-folder 51/5)
    - Cosi fan tutte (Box-folder 51/6)
    - Don Giovanni (Box-folder 51/7)
    - Erwartung; die glückliche Hand (Box-folder 51/8)
    - Falstaff (Box-folder 51/9)
    - Fidelio (Box-folder 51/10)
    - Der fliegende Holländer (Box-folder 51/11)
    - Hochzeit des Figaro (Box-folder 51/12)
    - Missa solemnis (Beethoven) (Box-folder 51/13)
    - Oedipus Rex (Box-folder 51/14)
    - Requiem (Verdi) (Box-folder 51/15)
    - Der Rosenkavalier (Box-folder 51/16)
    - St. John/St. Matthew passion (Bach) (Box-folder 51/17)
    - Tannhäuser (Box-folder 51/18)
    - Die Zauberflöte (Box-folder 51/19)
- Clippings, 1926-1972 (Box 106)
  Includes photocopies of newspaper clippings, press releases, articles, and typescripts.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - 1926-1972 (Box-folder 106/6)
- Programs, 1901-1967 (Box 51)
  Includes original programs and photocopies and typescripts of programs.
  Arranged alphabetically by organization, and chronologically therein.
  - A-K (Box-folder 51/20)
  - Los Angeles Philharmonic Orchestra (Box-folder 51/21)
  - Los Angeles Philharmonic Orchestra; Hollywood Bowl (Box-folder 51/22)
  - M-Z (Box-folder 51/23)
- Iconography, 1924-1971 (Box 101-102)
  Includes five photograph albums and one album of watercolors.
  - Buehnen Entwuerfe von Buchholz/Wiesbaden, 1924-1927 (Box 101/1)
  - Bis 1948 (Box 101/2)
  - 1949 bis 1969 (Box 101/3)
  - London, BBC-TV, May/June 1970 (Box 102/1)
  - London, Feb. and Sept. 1971 (Box 102/2)
  - All periods (Box 102/3)
- Miscellaneous Printed Matter, 1930-1977 (Box 52)
  Includes articles, books, programs, an opera libretto, and photocopies of encyclopedia entries.
  Arranged alphabetically by author, and by title therein.
  - Blonda, Max. Von heute auf morgen. (Box 52/1)
  - Blume, Friedrich. Die Musik in Geschichte und Gegenwart. (Box 52/2)
  - Bónis, F. Gustav Mahler und Ferenc Erkel. (Box 52/3)
  - Brandt, H. G. Betrachtungen zum Thema: Chanukah 5739. (Box 52/4)
  - Brod, Max. Gustav Mahler. (Box 52/5)
  - Fischer, Kurt von. Bemerkungen zu Gustav Mahlers Liedern. (Box 52/6)
  - Fischer, Kurt von. Die Doppelschlagfigur in den zwei letzten Sätze von Gustav Mahlers 9. Symphonie. (Box 52/7)
  - Fischer, Kurt von. Gustav Mahlers Umgang mit Wunderhorntexten. (Box 52/8)
  - Heyworth, Peter. Karmesterek és a karmesterség - Klemperer szemével. (Box 52/9)
  - Ingerslev-Jensen, Pavl. Isenstein. (Box 52/10)
  - Jacobi, Erwin R. Albert Schweitzer und Richard Wagner. (Box 52/11)
  - Jacobi, Erwin R. Die Musik im Leben und Schaffen von Albert Schweitzer. (Box 52/11)
  - Lipman-Wulf, Peter. About my sculpture Otto Klemperer Conducting. (Box 52/12)
  - Pfäfflin, Friedrich. Berthold Viertel [1885-1953], eine Dokumentation. (Box 52/13)
  - Plessner, Helmuth. Ein Volk der Dichter und Denker? (Box 52/14)
  - Plessner, Helmuth. Das Geheimnis des Schauspielers. (Box 52/14)
  - Plessner, Helmuth. Homo absconditus. (Box 52/14)
  - Plessner, Helmuth. Husserl in Göttingen. (Box 52/14)
  - Plessner, Helmuth. Über die gesellschaftlichen Bedingungen. (Box 52/14)
  - Plessner, Helmuth. Wiesbadener Kinderszenen. (Box 52/14)
  - Plessner, Helmuth. Zur Hermeneutik nichtsprachlichen Ausdrucks. (Box 52/14)
  - Schultz, Klaus, ed. Badener Musiktage, 1977. (Box 52/15)
  - Schweitzer, Albert. Concerning the Art and Personality of J. S. Bach. (Box 52/16)
  - Schweitzer, Albert. Unveröffentlichte Briefe an Margit Jacobi. (Box 52/16)
  - Schweitzer, Albert. Von Bachs Persönlich und Kunst. (Box 52/16)
  - Sellenthin, H. G. Geschichte der Juden in Berlin und des Gebäudes Fasanenstrasse 79/80. (Box 52/17)
  - Vondenhoff, Eleonore. Gustav Mahler Dokumentation. (Box 52/18)
  - Zelter, Karl Friedrich. Zum zweihundertsten Geburtstag. (Box 52/19)
- Klemperer Film Materials, 1885-1972 (Box 53-100, 106-108)
  - Writings (Box 53)
    Contains carbon copies and typescripts.
    - Bregstein, Philo. Montagescript Klempererfilm. (Box-folder 53/1)
    - Bregstein, Philo. Portrait of Otto Klemperer. (Box-folder 53/2)
    - Curjel, Hans. Die Berliner Krolloper. (Box-folder 53/3)
    - Klemperer, Otto. [Bach]. (Box-folder 53/4)
    - Klemperer, Otto. Der Dirigent Klemperer. (Box-folder 53/5)